# Uchenna Anya

Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria

martinsanya19@gmail.com

+2347062725781

linkedin.com/in/uchenna-anya

# **Summary**

I am a professional web developer with over 6(six) years of proven industry experience. Strong proficiency in JavaScript, ReactJS, AngularJS VueJS, and NodeJS and I worked with PHP, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails, I have worked with Docker, Microsoft Azure, and AWS to a good extent I am currently learning Kubernetes.

#### I have:

- Thorough understanding of React.js and its core principles
- Experience with popular React.js workflows (such as Flux or Redux)
- Knowledge of isomorphic React
- Thorough understanding of AngularJS and its core principles
- Familiarity with newer specifications of ECMAScript
- Experience with data structure libraries (e.g., Immutable.js)
- Thorough understanding of RESTful APIs
- Thorough understanding of NodeJS and its core principles
- Familiarity with PHP
- Familiarity with Docker
- Familiarity with Microsoft Azure
- Familiarity with AWS

#### Soft Skills:

Teaching, conflict resolution, teamwork, collaboration, and communication

PORTFOLIO: https://uchennaanya.netlify.app/ GITHUB: https://github.com/uchennaanya/

# **Experience**

# Full-stack web developer (MERN) stack

MRSoft International Nig. Ltd.

Jan 2022 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.

Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.

Identifying web-based user interactions.

Developing and implementing highly responsive user interface components using react concepts.

Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following react.js workflows.

Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.

Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.

Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

Documenting application changes and developing updates.

#### Freelance Software Developer

Sep 2018 - Apr 2022 (3 years 8 months)

As a freelancer I have worked on projects using a couple of web development tools such as HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Sass, Javascript, Reactjs, PHP, Ruby, Ruby on rails, etc.



#### **Frontend Engineer**

Port Harcourt Agents

Dec 2019 - Nov 2021 (2 years)

A property company in the heart of Rivers State, Nigeria that solves the problem associated with getting a house for rent or purchase

Tech: HTML5, Bootstrap, Javascript, ReactJs, AngularJs, and Docker

I designed and built the front end from the ground up, using ReactJs and Redux, HTML5, Bootstrap

I consumed and contributed to a RESTful API built with NodeJs and its associated dependencies and containerized it with Docker.

I wrote unit and integration tests using jest.

I followed the agile methodology and followed every industry standard.



#### Andela

Jun 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year 3 months)

I Learned JavaScript, AngularJs, PWA, Web accessibility, and CSS3. During the internship, I collaborated with senior developers working on projects.



#### **HNG Internship**

May 2020 - Aug 2020 (4 months)

This is a 100% remote internship program, I made use of collaborative tools like git and github, slack, zoom and google meet collaborating with fellow interns around I implemented a lot of designs from professional UI, UX designer under the world-class project manager that reviewed my implementations to make sure they meet the required standard.

#### Web Developer

AspireLabs!

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018 (8 months)

Built and maintained the company web site Built clients web sites and maintained them



#### Web Developer

#### SalesBay

Nov 2017 - Aug 2018 (10 months)

Built the backend of the business website with PHP



**RAD5 Tech Hub** 

Mar 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 6 months)

I Learned and implemented the concept of OOP, modern web development, Php, and JS

#### **Education**



#### Microverse

Computer Software Engineering

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021

- 1190+ hours of mastering data structures and algorithms while honing my skills as a full-stack software developer (Rails | Ruby on Rails | React | Redux).
- Design and Rebuilt UI/UX projects using [ SASS ] [ CSS3 ] [ HTML5 ] | [ BOOTSTRAP ].
- · Develop Fully-fledged web-based apps using Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, and more, keeping in mind software security.
- · Immersive training in remote pair programming by collaborating with software developers across the globe. Also, daily stand-up meetings ensured proper communication skills (both descriptive and technical).
- · Adopt excellent coding practices. This entailed: getting acquainted with industry-standard git workflows, software developer life cycle (agile, waterfall), and the embracing of code linting/automation tools ensured code quality and integrity.

### Akanu Ibiam Federal Polytechnic

Computer Science

- · Conducted a free and fair election
- Worked with a group of other members to achieve success in election processes

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Microverse Ruby/Databases Module - Microverse

27358881



M Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS - Microverse



Certificate of Appreciation - DevTown

- Certificate of Completion-Nodejs DevTown
- **Certificate of Course Completion** Google for Developers 63479DFC68F427E2
- Jobberman Soft Skills Course Jobberman Nigeria
  GX57EP29R7LN

Certificate of Completion Javascript and ReactJs - GDG RANCHI Z1hwkjX

- Certificate of Completion Javascript and ReactJs DevTown 7k3Gd
- React JS- Complete Guide for Frontend Web Development [2021] EdYoda Digital University
- in Learning React.js LinkedIn
- Certificate of Completion Udemy
- HTML and CSS in depth Meta YRJTLU5FT7YJ
- Version Control Meta 4AWWTXV2LKZX
- Coding Interview Preparation Meta 5TZDV7EQD7Q6
- Programming with JavaScript Meta 64JS444TG238
- Principles of UX/UI Design Meta

#### N55AWAWE8QXY

#### Advance ReactJs - Meta

GRZTJCQ6K23F

# Front-End Developer Capstone - Meta

LLC4VWXMZADZ

## Meta Front-End Developer Specialization - Meta

MYVGWVKYEWJ6

# **Skills**

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Functional Programming • Unit Testing • Front-end Engineering • Data Structures • GitHub • User Experience (UX) • UI/UX • User Personas • Web Development